And this is like the core editor
experience. But then in the CLI we also
have um cursor agent which is the same
idea but you could use it anywhere
really. You could use this in a
different editor. You could use it in
your CI uh anywhere you want. So I'll
run this just so you can get a idea of
what this looks like but it's very
similar idea. It's just a different
interface for the same agentic idea of
working with an AI model. This is Lee
Robinson, a legendary developer who
scaled Versel from one to $200 million
ARR and now he works at Cursor as the
head of AI education. If you are serious
about coding with AI, you have to watch
this video. Who do you think is going to
benefit from AI the most? Is it the
junior developers or the senior guys?
>> So I think today the more senior
engineer benefits a bit more. But I
think towards the future it will empower
people who start learning to code with
AI. they're going to just develop skills
in a different way than maybe the more
senior engineer.
>> So, what's like one thing you notice
among the top users of AI that can use
it the most efficiently that maybe
beginners or like a lot of vibe coders
don't do?
>> Yeah, there's kind of a spectrum of
different AI tools that you can use for
coding. It really goes to how much
autonomy you want to give the AI tool or
the AI agent. So, in the most basic
example, it's just predicting the next
action that you want to take in the
editor. So, GitHub Copilot, you know,
made this popular. Basically,
autocomplete for your code, right? But
it's gotten better over the years. So, I
think the people who are farther along
on that journey are kind of in the AI
agent world and they're trying to figure
out the right way to put the right rules
and checks in place so that the agent
can write code and it's not just
immediately throwaway code or not
actually useful. like you have to figure
out how to constrain this generator of
code that will spit out things that
might look correct but are not actually
correct.
>> Yeah. One one example that I've done
recently is like writing front-end
tests. Really making sure the first
three of them are well documented. I
think this is what I noticed is like the
best users of AI put in more time up
front and then can just go way faster.
Whereas a lot of the beginners, they
just want a quick MVP, quick website and
then they maybe go in a direction that
they didn't want to go in.
>> Yeah. And also I think in putting more
time up front there's also an
understanding of what do I want to even
build and having more specificity and
it's not that you have to write you know
a book on a prompt but you need to know
the specifics of the system that you're
building and what you'll notice from
more experienced engineers is they can
give very precise language on the thing
that they're trying to build that's
going to be able to steer the AI in the
right direction.
>> It really comes down to software design
at the end of the day. If I'm like going
to add a big feature with AI, I don't
even want to look at the code until I
have complete understanding, right? And
I think that that's literally the like
staying in charge. That's the main
thing.
>> Yeah. There's no substitute for the
business requirements or like the
product spec because
>> the AI will happily generate whatever
code it wants given a vague PRD or a
vague document that's trying to describe
what you're what you want to build. As
we go into the age of AI coding, what do
you think is going to be like the most
important skill to learn and master?
>> Just trying to use the tools and I think
critically learning where they're not
very good. As the models get better, as
the tools get better, you're kind of
trying to push up against where the
models are bad. Have a very good
understanding of where the current
capabilities aren't good enough yet,
such that when new functionality comes
out, you kind of know, okay, I can go
try this thing now. Yeah, it really is
like developing that taste of when to
use the model, when to not use the
model. You know, people, especially like
the CEOs of the AI labs, they like to
hype everything up like you know, within
6 months 90% of the code or all the code
is going to be written by AI. But the
reality is probably somewhere in the
middle, right?
>> Yeah. It's like both sides are somewhat
right and both sides are somewhat wrong.
Yes, AI is another tool in the tool belt
that we will continue to use and get
better at to help us write code better
and design software better. But I think
this dream or this idea that somehow
it's just going to write all the code is
is not very realistic.
>> Yeah, I agree. Why do you think the CLI
tools are becoming so popular? I think
this is one of the most unexpected
trends of this year. It's almost
counterintuitive, right? Like the more
minimalistic the interface. You would
think that it would be some fancy UI
that's becoming the way to use AI
agents, but it turns out it's the
terminal.
>> Yeah. So, the reason for this is that
there's a different level of autonomy
that you want when working with the AI
model. And for some people, they prefer
to write most of the code still and they
like having the kind of autocomplete
like cursor tab where it's going to help
them predict the next action as they're
coding kind of staying in the flow. And
for those people, they are kind of happy
with editors that are like cursor or IDs
like cursor or maybe bringing that
experience somewhere else. Then as you
kind of move up the abstraction and you
allow people to use models with agents
to write a lot more code, the interface
for what that looks like is still kind
of being figured out. The best way of
doing that. And the nice thing about a
CLI and the reason why we invested in
building a CLI is that it allows them to
use the cursor agent that when they want
that part of coding with AI in really
any of those editors. And an underrated
one is that it can be used in your CI or
it can be used on a server. It can just
be used anywhere really. And that's one
of the nice things about taking the
brain of the cursor agent and just
making it available on any UI surface.
>> Yes. So I guess it's easier for people
who have their workflow to adapt it
rather than switching to, you know, a
different software. Makes sense. All
right. So can we jump into cursor and
can you show us something that you
yourself like to do? I'll just do like a
lightning round of some of the features
inside of cursor for people who are
maybe newer to the product or are kind
of newer to AI coding in general. Uh and
then al also sprinkle in some things for
those who have kind of been around for a
while. So I've got a just a blank cursor
window open here and I'm just going to
start a new project for this example. I
think there's pros and cons of both. The
new project is a little bit easier to
show in this time frame, but I'd say
most of the time you're also kind of
making changes to an existing codebase.
The reason I wanted to show this is
because one project that I like bun,
which is, you know, runtime, package
manager, a whole bunch of stuff. Uh,
they have this bun init command where
you can go pick whatever you want. And
we can see it's going to make a bunch of
stuff here. Great. Actually, let me make
a new directory. Now, I'm going to pick
React. We'll use that. Sure. Great. So,
we can see kind of what we have inside
of here. That looks awesome. Now, you
notice it made a dot cursor, which is
very interesting. Let's actually open
this up. Okay. So, now you know how I
mentioned there's kind of the different
levels of uh autonomy you want to give.
Like the agents on the right, that's
going to allow it to write, you know,
the most amount of code. We're just
going to close that for a minute. Um,
and I want to show one thing I like from
Bunanit, which is that it automatically
kind of sets up your editor to know
about the tool. So it says hey you know
here are some of the things that bun
provides some of the APIs it provides
specific code examples of things that
you can do and there's a really
interesting one way down at the bottom
it actually ships the API docs in the
node modules which I find really really
interesting. So I think there's going to
be a trend where we see more packages,
more libraries, more tools include
specific rules,
you know, bundled in the the tooling
that sets them up. And then also I think
the industry is starting to move towards
a standardization uh for an agents.md.
So cursing now supports this as well if
you don't want to do cursor specific
rules so that it will work really with
any AI coding tool that you want to use.
Yeah, I think like in general there will
be a trend of building code bases for
agents like you know whether it's cloud
MD whether it's cursor MDC files whether
it's agent.m MD I think it will probably
standardize itself right but it's going
to be like every folder is going to have
a markdown file probably that is
instructions of what's in that folder
how to use it when when to interact with
it specifically for AI agents but also
it will serve as an internal
documentation for new human developers
>> yep 100% and I I think um going back to
my kind of autonomy thing, if you
haven't seen cursor tab before, I might
do something like function and it's
giving me the ghost text to complete. If
you've used co-pilot before, you've seen
this before. But another cool thing here
um is I don't know, let's say
>> I wanted to do yeah something like this
where I'm doing a counter. Now you see I
get this suggestion to do an import and
it can tab to include the imports which
is a really nice feature. I'm a big fan
of that. So that's like the most basic
example where
>> yeah everyone should use this like
>> yeah it's like it's a no-brainer like
that's going to save you a ton of time.
Another one that I think maybe some
people not everybody uses but if you go
highlight some code you can also command
K and now you're editing just this
specific block. So maybe I want use uh
you know use a picture element instead.
>> Yeah. I feel like command K is fallen a
bit in the background. Don't you think?
>> Yeah. Command K. I think a lot of people
still really like it. I think there's
kind of a a preference of do I want to
be kind of in the flow of this file
writing code and I just want to make
these very surgical like single changes
or do I want to give the the agent the
ability to do whatever it wants. So this
is like the way I describe it is the two
things I just showed. So doing
autocomplete with cursor tab doing
things with command K. This is like I'm
not using AI today and I'm wanting to
get into it. Yes,
>> these are the most like basic practical
ways for you to do it where the the
value ad is very high. When you start to
then go and you open up the agent view,
we've now kind of opened up this new
portal of complexity that has a lot of
uh additional challenges with it. So,
for example, we might say um I'm making
a personal finance app to track my
spending.
Let's add a table to view this data.
Sure. Now, already there's just a lot of
stuff in here that if this is your first
time kind of looking at the tool, you're
trying to figure out how all these
things work. There's the agent mode, so
it can go write code for you. There's
the model selection, which there's a lot
of different models in here. Uh maybe
I'll just do auto for the sake of this,
but you can pick specific models if you
would like. You can attach images.
Great. So now you're kind of setting an
AI model off to go do a bunch of stuff
and you're seeing it just have all this
output where it's reading files, it's
listing files, it's going and making new
changes. And this is where I think those
who are kind of newer to coding with AI,
it can feel really great at first, but
this is also where there's kind of some
core concepts on here that you need to
understand to be successful. The first
is that this entire chat, this entire
conversation is part of one context
window or one conversation. So, as I'm
asking more questions, as I'm building
more, you're going to see at the end of
the generation, there's going to be a
little progress bar. And as that
progress bar gets higher to 100%.
Usually, and there's some early research
showing the the quality of the model
response usually goes down as you get up
to the top of that context. context.
>> Now the the you know the the next
question might be okay well then I just
need to use a context window that's you
know a million tokens or 10 million
tokens if that existed. And the answer
is kind of more tricky than that. It
doesn't actually just uh magically make
things better to have a 2 million or 10
million uh you know token context
window. Instead you really want to be
precise about the changes that you're
making. So just this one change where we
said okay we want to make this table it
used some tool calls. So it's like
calling a function in you know a
programming language it calls some
function it gets some information back
we read some files we uh made some code
changes we applied those code changes uh
and we can go review the changes.
>> So let me just make this a little
smaller and we can kind of step through
with this um kind of picker down at the
bottom here and go through each of the
individual changes. There's also changes
in three different files. So we have
this table component. Um we have the
spending tracker and then we have the
actual changes inside of the app. Now if
all these look good, I can just hit
keep. So this is kind of the flow. Keep.
Great. Awesome. I'll keep all of these.
And we used uh about 11% here of the
context window on auto. Now the thing
that I see a lot of people do
incorrectly is then they just keep
going. You know, there's like okay like
it's already got all this context. I'm
just going to keep like make another
feature. Uh and that can be problematic
because even you might think, okay,
there's some information in this context
I want to continue along in the next
conversation. But uh it's kind of
counterintuitive, but there can be
little bits of information in there that
accidentally steer the model in the
wrong direction. So maybe in one
conversation you mentioned something
about using git and making commits and
then if you keep going, you notice that
the model just keeps making commits all
the time. And that's not necessarily a
bad thing, but you kind of planted that
seed in the model's brain and it's using
it every single time now. So maybe what
I would actually want is to, you know,
commandn or start a new chat and
actually do something discreet and
specific for this one um, you know, this
one feature I want to add. And there's a
whole skill of managing the information
that you give to the agent so that it
has just the right amount of stuff. Like
I mentioned, like too much stuff is
going to throw it off. But then also, if
I just say like make it better.
>> Yeah,
>> that's not enough information. I need to
give it some rules, which this is what
this is showing. There's a rule
included. And then it already knows I
have this code open in this tab, so it
can include that. But I can also use the
at and include a bunch of different
information. One of the underrated ones
I like is branch. So if you've been
working uh on changes for a while, you
can say like review all the changes in
my branch and it can kind of understand
the context of all the changes so far.
>> So like before making a PR just to like
clean it up, making sure everything is
good before you send it to like a
>> Yes, definitely. So we could go in here
and we could go make more changes, but I
think that's the the general idea of you
can do autocomplete, you can do inline
changes, you can use the agent to make
more bits of code. And this is like the
core editor experience. But then in the
CLI we also have um cursor agent which
is the same idea but you could use it
anywhere really. You could use this in a
different editor. You could use it in
your CI uh anywhere you want. Um explain
this repo.
>> So I'll run this just so you can get a
idea of what this looks like but it's
very similar idea. It's just a different
interface for the same agentic idea of
working with an AI model. You can change
models here just like you can um in the
cursor editor. And the the the
philosophy of cursor is we want to allow
you to use any model. So as new models
come out, which they come out like once
a month, right? Seems like there's
always new models. They're always going
to be trying new things and making
improvements. Our goal is to support all
of those models and make it very easy to
integrate them into your application and
get the kind of the best of all of the
latest tech.
>> Yeah. And I feel like it the future as
the models get better and more capable
is going to be more heavily about the UI
like reviewing tons of changes because
nobody wants you know 2,000 lines diff
and just like insanely difficult to see
what the AI did. It's going to be more
about like how do I review this quickly
before improving.
>> Yep. Now the other thing I want to show
like as you're as you're in the process
of working through building software,
I'm in my editor. I'm making changes. I
work with the agent. I I say go add this
thing or go add another thing and I'm
working on building the software
project. But eventually over time the
project's going to get a little bit
bigger. Maybe multiple people are going
to work on it and you're not always
going to be directly in your editor. So
it was very important for us to take
this same cursor agent experience and
bring it to a bunch of different places
trying to make every part of building
software easier with AI. So let me show
a different screen just as uh an
example. One thing that we added
recently that maybe not as many people
know about is the ability to call the
same cursor agent but from Slack.
>> So um on installing the cursor agent, I
wanted to make it so that there's a curl
command that says go to
cursor.com/install. But if you went to
this URL in the browser, I said ah let's
actually make that just redirect to our
marketing page. uh if the user agent is
a browser and our agent just like we
could call it in the editor, we can also
call it in Slack or we can go to
cursor.com/agents and call it from there
as well.
>> And then it can make a PR for us and we
can go review those changes, make sure
everything looks okay and then merge it.
So I I'm often making a bunch of changes
to cursor without ever really needing to
be in the editor. I can call things from
Slack, I can call things from the web, I
can call things from a CLI. Some people
use like CLIs on their phone. I've seen
levels I talk about this quite a bit
which is fun. Um and the goal is just to
try to bring that agent experience
pretty much wherever you're at.
>> So that kind of nicely ties into the
topic of MCPS, right? Because they also
make it more integrated where agents can
use different tools or even different
agents. Talk about MCPs. What do you see
the future there? I mentioned that the
agent has the ability to call tools and
the tools are like reading files or
listing files or applying code changes,
searching the web. These are all tools
that are built in that cursor or the AI
tool is defining. So we're giving the
agent, let's call it 10 different really
high quality tools. Yes.
>> And for some of those tools, by the way,
cursor has our own models that we've
trained to be really good at just that
one thing. So indexing a codebase and
searching over a codebase and and so on.
Now the great thing about MCP is that it
allows you to add arbitrary tools into
that list. So you can integrate with
basically any external system then
whether you write the MCP server or they
write the MCP server and it allows it to
have a tool that can go call something
could be an API could be a CLI could be
anything and then bring that information
back and put it into the context. So,
going back to what I mentioned, like
context management is kind of the key
skill, knowing what you're putting in.
Um, the size of the context window,
making sure it doesn't get too large.
When you go call an MCP and you go bring
some information back and put it inside
of there, that's really helpful context.
It can be great for the agent to solve
the task or go look at my runtime logs
or go look at observability data. All
that's great, but then you also need to
know those kind of foundational concepts
you're building on like the context,
size, what are tool calls, how does that
grow over time? So the future of MCP for
me I think is there's kind of two
different modes. There's people using
MCPs with AI chats like chat GBT on the
web or something which this is like it's
more of a connector of things. It's
basically integrations so I can connect
to my Google Drive account and go pull
information from there. That's fine. I
think there's some
>> uh security things there that are
tricky. There's already been some
there's already been some cases where
you have to be very careful about giving
a model access to all of your Google
Drive and you know Google email account
uh because models can hallucinate and
they maybe would get something wrong or
they might run a command that
accidentally you know delete something
in your Google Drive. So yeah,
>> I'm I'm much more of a readonly MCP
person for like most things. Like
reading stuff is is mostly fine. It's
the writing stuff you have to be a lot
more careful of, which is why in cursor
like when you're in the agent, you can
allow or deny specific commands that you
want to uh give the MCP the ability to
to use. So that's like more of the
consumer side. On the developer side,
the the MCP use cases I'm excited about
are tools and frameworks and companies
making MCP servers that make it easier
for models to ingest data about that
product. So maybe it's the runtime logs
or the observability data or the account
information. Just getting that
information back into the MCB server
such that when you're trying to debug an
issue and it's some kind of runtime
error, you can say okay let's go look at
X account and figure out what went wrong
and it can go to Sentry or something for
example and go to Sentry. It can look at
all the errors that have happened. it
can pull that into the context and
generally the model does a better job of
kind of finding that information in a
stream of just raw logs than it would
take for a human to find that.
>> So last question I want to ask is if you
had to leave the next generation of
software engineers with one piece of
advice, what would that be? I think that
it's uncomfortable for experienced
developers to see this new wave of tools
coming and feel like it's kind of
changing what it means to be a software
engineer and they they want to dismiss
it and kind of push it away or they're
kind of ignored or uh they're kind of
ignoring it or they're just upset about
the hype around AI. But I think that
this next generation is going to be very
AI native AI first. They're starting
learning using these tools. this is kind
of the way that they know how to build
software which has pros and cons but I
think can be they can learn the
downsides of that approach um probably
faster than people who have been coding
for 20 years and are kind of reluctant
to try this out are going to be able to
get a a feel for how working with models
um actually is. So I would say for those
kind of getting into coding right now,
the next generation, it's both important
to really understand how models work,
kind of become proficient as these tools
get better and better, but also you
can't skip the foundations. You're going
to get into a spot where the model's
wrong and you say, "Okay, go fix it.
Okay, it doesn't actually work." And you
say, "No, go fix that again." And you
just get into this cycle where it's kind
of just busted. And unless you have a
deeper understanding of how to debug
software and some of the core
principles, uh it could be kind of
frustrating. So I would highly recommend
both becoming AI native but also go
learn the CS foundations.
>> Yeah, you have to be willing to get your
hands dirty. And I think the the biggest
leverage is really upskilling yourself
because the models are going to get
better. AI tools are going to get better
and if you yourself use them to improve
your programming experience, you're just
going to outperform everybody else.
>> Yeah. Yeah. 100%. Riley, I appreciate
the time. So, what should people do?
Should they follow you on Twitter?
Should they check out Cursor?
>> Yeah. Um, I am posting about building
with AI, coding with AI on Twitter. Um,
Lero and then also we're releasing a
course on how to use AI. Cursor is it'll
be free. It'll be online at
cursor.com/learn
in the coming weeks or month or maybe
already available when you watch this
video.
>> Awesome. So, again, thank you for taking
the time and have a great day.
Thank you.